Zankoku na tenshi no you ni
Just like the cruel angel
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Young boy, become a legend
2D4U PRESENTS:
Aoi kaze ga ima
Even though the untested breeze...
mune no doa o tataitemo
...taps at the door to your heart
Watashi dake o tada mitsumete hohoenderu anata
You just look solely at me and smile
Sotto fureru mono motomeru koto ni muchuu de
So intent on seeking out that gentle touch
Unmei sae mada shiranai itaike na hitomi
Such innocent eyes, still ignorant of their destiny
Dakedo itsuka kizuku deshou
But someday, you are sure to realize...
sono senaka ni wa
...that upon your back
Haruka mirai mezasu tame
You have the wings with which to fly...
no hane ga aru koto
...towards the distant future
Zankoku na tenshi no teeze
The cruel angel's thesis
Madobe kara yagate tobidatsu
Soon, you will take flight from the windowsill
Hotobashiru atsui patosu de
With your torrent of ardent pathos
Omoide o uragiru nara
If you are to betray our memories
Kono sora o daite kagayaku
You, who embrace these heavens and shine
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Young boy, become a legend
Is he going to skip school again?
Little Shin's Room
Shinji, wake up! How long are you going
to keep skipping school?
It's been five days now. Unit 01 has
already been completely repaired.
So don't you think the pilot needs
to get his act together too?
Shinji?!
Miss Misato Katsuragi
He's run away.
I suppose that's not surprising.
EPISODE 04
RAIN, AFTER RUNNING AWAY
Shinji?
Well...
We're Ikari's classmates,
Aida and Suzuhara, Ma'am.
Aida and Suzuhara?
Yes, Ma'am!
I'm Suzuhara.
Aren't you the boys who got in
Unit 01's entry plug?
Yes, Ma'am!
We're sorry for causing so much trouble.
Actually, Ikari's been absent ever since then,
so we came to see if he was okay.
He's at the Nerv training facility right now.
Oh, I see.
These are the printouts that were
building up on Ikari's desk.
Oh, sorry for your trouble. Thank you.
Well, we'll be leaving now.
Please say "hi" to Ikari for us.
Yeah, I will. Bye.
This is an unexpected development.
She was a real babe, wasn't she?
Shinji, you idiot!
Idiot!
The next station is
Nagao Toge, Nagao Toge.
The exit will switch to the right side.
Thank you for using New Tokyo-3
Loop Seven.
This train will be going out of service
at this station.
Please, make sure you take all of your
belongings as you exit the train.
I've got to go back.
Hey there! We're offering you
a great bargain!
Hot young babes serving
heavenly refreshment!
Special services to heal your tired body,
services to fill you with energy!
You really couldn't detect it, Doctor?!!
Yes. An object only ten
millimeters in diameter
crashed into Antarctica at close
to the speed of light.
The technology we had was unable
to predict or prevent such a thing.
It's like hell out there! Just what is
the purpose of science?!
The atmospheric flux caused by the
change in the Earth's axis
has decreased by 3%.
So it's getting a little better?
No, there's still a tidal wave approaching
at 230 meters a second!
Doctor! We must evacuate!
It's my duty to remain here.
Doctor, choosing death is easy,
but you have an obligation
to watch this living hell!
Documentary!
The World Sinks...
Second Impact
Tokyo-2
Tokyo
Idiot.
Arrival Stop Only
He's only fourteen years old.
It seems so cruel, making him bear
the burden of mankind's destiny.
But we have no choice but to entrust the
piloting of the Evas to fourteen year olds.
I know.
So, has he called?
No?
No. I think he might never come back.
What are you going to do?
Nothing really.
If he won't come back,
maybe that's for the better.
Why?
After the battle the other day...
Why did you ignore my order?
I'm sorry.
I'm the one who's in charge
of your operations, right?
Yes.
You have a duty to obey my orders.
Do you understand?
Yes.
I'm warning you, never do it again.
Do you really understand what I'm saying?!
Yes.
Hey, you're not going to get out of this
by just saying yes to everything I say.
I know that. That's enough, isn't it?
We won the battle anyway.
You know, it may seem easy to go along
with whatever anyone else wants,
but if you get into the Eva with that attitude,
it'll kill you!
I don't care.
It'd be nice if I could say you've got
the right attitude,
but if you expect to get any praise out of me,
you're wrong, Shinji Ikari.
That's not the point. In any case, I'm the
only one who can pilot it, aren't I?
I'll do it.
I see.
If piloting an Eva means nothing
but pain to him,
he shouldn't get into it again.
Otherwise, I'm sure he'll get killed.
But we need pilots.
Captain!
Aida, go on ahead!
But I can't go and leave you behind!
You fool!
Upsy-daisy.
The new kid?
Ikari!
Summer Training Drill Operation Outline
Today's Scheduled Operations
15:00 Deploy for Combat
16:00 Prepare for Attack,
Commence Firing
Toji was sorry about that.
He said that his kid sister scolded him
and said that, "It was the robot
who saved our lives!"
That's pretty embarrassing, being
chewed out by a grade school kid.
Right?
I like it at night because those
noisy cicadas don't chirp.
Although I remember that it was pretty quiet
when I was a kid,
there've been more of them each year.
The ecosystem is returning
to its former state.
That's what Miss Misato said.
I see, Miss Misato said so.
I really envy you.
Living with such a beautiful woman
and piloting the Evangelion.
I wish I could get behind
the controls just once!
You shouldn't. I think your mother
would be worried.
Oh, don't worry about that. I don't have one.
I'm the same as you.
You'll have something to eat, won't you?
Yeah.
Do you usually do this sort of thing?
Huh? Well, sure.
Is this some kind of training for
guerilla warfare or something?
How could I fight with toys like these?
It's just for fun.
You're Shinji Ikari, aren't you?
Yes.
We're from Nerv Security Intelligence.
Under Article 8 of the Security Act,
we're taking you to headquarters.
All right?
Yes.
And all you did was stand there?
That's easy for you to say!
But it's like I said, they were Nerv
Security Intelligence, professionals.
So what?! Don't you have any balls at all?!
Sissy!
Pervert!
Ape!
Only an idiot fights when
he knows he can't win.
Balls have nothing to do with it.
Long time, no see.
Yes.
Do you feel any better after wandering
around for two days?
I don't know.
The Eva is on standby. Will you pilot it?
Or won't you?
You're not going to scold me
for running away?
Of course not. I'm not related to you, am I?
If I say that I won't pilot Unit 01,
what will you do with it?
I suppose that Rei will do it.
Won't you pilot it?
It seems unrealistic for you
to force everything on her.
Don't worry. I'll pilot it.
But you don't want to do it?
Of course not. To begin with, it's not
something that comes to me naturally.
But Ayanami, Miss Misato and Miss Ritsuko...
Cut that out!
This has nothing to do with any of us!
If you don't like it, get out of here!
Just forget all about Eva and us and
go back to where you came from!
We don't need someone
with that attitude piloting!
The Third Child is leaving
New Tokyo-3 tomorrow.
Then we'll reconfigure
Unit 01's system for Rei.
But...
Regardless of the results of Unit 00's
re-activation experiments,
we'll move on to experimenting with Unit 01.
According to the Marduk
Organization's report,
the Fourth Child hasn't been found yet.
That means we can't get
any pilot replacements?
Excuse me, where is Miss Misato?
I'd like to say goodbye.
You're no longer Nerv personnel.
Therefore, we can't give you any information.
Ikari!
You forgot this!
Could you excuse me for a moment?
Thank you.
Hey, Toji.
Come on, say something!
Ikari, I'm sorry I hit you twice.
Please, hit me back!
I can't do that.
Please! Otherwise, I won't be satisfied.
See? He's a pretty embarrassing guy,
isn't he?
But if it'll put an end to this dispute,
why don't you go ahead and hit him?
But...
Hurry up! You don't have
much time, do you?
Okay, but only once.
Okay! Come on!
Hold it!
No holdin' back.
Right.
Ouch...
How did you know I'd be here?
Call it a hunch. We've seen
dozens of classmates off now.
If you're leavin', we'll have to leave
this city sometime soon,
but we can't blame you for that.
We saw how you suffered in the Eva.
And if anyone tries to blame you,
I'm gonna give them a head butt!
Hey, don't look so gloomy.
Take care.
Good luck!
Well...
It's time.
I'm the one who deserves to be hit!
I'm a scoundrel, a coward,
spineless and weak...
Don't give us any more trouble.
Eva Unit 01 will be entering Stage 2
cryo-stasis for activation system rewrite.
He's gone.
Was it for the best?
The "Hedgehog's Dilemma".
The closer we become,
the more deeply we hurt each other.
Now I understand.
That boy...
He can't let others know how he feels
in any other way.
The Express Linear Train bound
for Atsugi is arriving on Track 2.
For your safety, please step back
to the area inside the yellow lines.
The train arriving on Track 2 is for
special government use only
and departs at 4:20 for Atsugi.
No civilians are allowed inside the fence.
Please be aware that the
boarding of this train
by unauthorized persons
is strictly prohibited.
Hang in there.
Look!
It's that babe!
The local train bound for Gora
is now arriving on Track 4.
For your own safety, please stay
inside the yellow lines.
If you're accompanying small children,
please ensure that they are
properly supervised.
The train arriving on Track 4 is the
local shuttle to Gora departing at 4:32.
If this is your train, please step inside
and wait until departure.
The train is now approaching.
Please stay behind the yellow line.
I... I'm home.
Welcome home.
TO BE CONTINUED
PREVIEW
Rei Ayanami limits her association
with others as much as possible.
The only one she opens up to
is Commander lkari.
Shinji is at a loss to understand this girl,
who is closer to his own father than he is.
Next Evangelion: "Rei, Beyond the Heart"
REI, BEYOND THE HEART